- Previously on Gotham...
- Watch out!
Ivy's missing.
She'll turn up somewhere.
It was a long way down into water.
What's your name? My name's Ivy.
- Who the hell are you?
- Not yet.
This is too fun.
He loves me and I love him.
I am telling you one last time,
let Ed go.
- No.
- Very well.
Don't say I didn't warn you.
Oh, no.
Somebody help!
I want to rejoin the GCPD.
Welcome back, Detective.
Captain, I'm so glad you came.
I came to congratulate you.
If a person comes into contact
with my blood, it changes them.
You and I are gonna
make a difference in this city.
We're gonna clean it up.
Sentence served.
Symon.
Who did this?
Barnes.
So, seems anyone
could have gotten access
to that bathroom, not just the guests.
Suspect pool's wide open.
All right, start with statements
from everyone at the party.
Someone saw Symon go into that bathroom.
Okay.
I still can't believe it.
I'm sorry things went down this way.
Don't apologize; you were right.
Did you give your statement already?
I'm afraid I wasn't very helpful.
Till about an hour ago,
I couldn't pick Symon
out of a crowd.
Did you talk to Barnes at the party?
A little. We had a drink.
Symon died around 10:30.
The attack happened just before.
What time did you talk with Barnes?
9:00.
What is this about?
- Nothing.
- Nothing? Really?
I can't talk about it.
No.
Lee, I cannot talk about it.
Jim, I hope you know what you're doing.
Me, too.
Barnes? No. No, no, no, no, no.
I asked Symon who attacked him,
and he said Barnes.
Symon was a psychopath
who gave face transplants to the mob
using stolen faces.
Hardly a credible witness.
And this guy, Barnes?
If he so much as jaywalked,
- he would write himself a ticket.
- I know.
"And now you're saying
he went to Lee Thompkin"
engagement party, and out of
nowhere, busted some guy's face
and chucked him through a wall?
- I know, Harvey.
- What's the motive?
- I don't know, maybe he...
He saw Symon,
he got pissed he was released,
and he lost control.
Okay. So, you're saying
that a man with a
spotless 20-year career,
just went ape. Is-is that your theory?
Something's been off about him recently.
You yourself said he
nearly beat Tetch to death.
And what's with him
insisting on running point
- in the Paulie Pennies case?
- Look,
I don't know, but that
does not make him a killer.
So where is he now?
Home. He spent the
better part of yesterday
chasing down Symon, maybe he's tired.
That doesn't mean he's guilty.
The last thing I want is
for Barnes to be guilty.
I look up to the man.
But if there is even a
chance then we have to know.
And something doesn't feel right.
Okay, okay, okay. I'm gonna help you.
But just so you know,
I'm doing it to prove
he's innocent, not guilty.
That's fine. All right, so
I'll go back to the scene,
see if forensics can pull
some prints from the bathroom.
Barnes's should already be on file.
Jim. I know how to do my job.
I hope I'm wrong.
Yeah. Me, too.
It starts as a whisper.
You have to strain to hear it.
And then it grows louder and louder,
till it becomes a roar.
It's everything you can
do to just shut it out.
And just like that...
you suddenly realize it's your voice.
The one you've been denying.
Telling you who you are.
What you have to do.
And then you stop fighting.
And this calm comes over you.
Sex trafficking.
Drugs.
Murder.
I've kept files on all
three of you for years.
Waiting for the proof we needed
while you sneered at the law.
Not tonight.
Tonight, I am the law!
And you are hereby tried.
Found guilty.
And sentenced.
Justice is served.
- Sync and corrections by madhatters -
- www.addic7ed.com -
So what's an antiquities dealer?
I buy and sell rare
and beautiful objects.
I like to think I have
an eye for beauty.
Is this a bug?
An Egyptian scarab.
More than 3,000 years old.
It's priceless.
Everything has a price.
What's upstairs?
The bedroom.
Hmm.
And the vault.
Vault?
It's where I keep my most
valuable acquisitions.
Can I see?
Ivy,
you are very beautiful.
But we've only just met.
We haven't had time to
get to know each other.
Who are you?
Where do you come from?
What do you do?
Well, I'm from Gotham.
And I meet men.
Like you.
They give me things.
And what do you give them?
Nothing.
I also like plants.
I've always been able to
get them to grow for me.
Lately, I've been using
them to make perfume.
Plants are so much more
powerful than people imagine.
They can poison you, heal you,
make you fall in love.
I made this from a strain
of cananga odorata.
Smell.
Now, open the vault.
COMPUTERIZED WOMAN'S
VOICE: Access granted.
Did they send you? You lying schlampe!
Did they?
Come back here!
You hear me? I'll find you!
- Everything okay?
- Fine.
You've been checking
your watch all morning.
You expecting... A call from Isabella.
She's at her librarian conference.
Ah.
Probably just busy.
Most likely.
I can imagine librarian conferences
can be hectic affairs.
- Not so much.
- Well,
I'm sure she'll call soon.
Hello.
This is Edward Nygma.
Why?
Very well.
That was the GCPD.
They want to see me. Wouldn't say why.
Oh?
You don't think that
something happened...
No!
The officer said Isabella
blew through a red light
and crashed into a train.
They think she might've
fallen asleep at the wheel.
Yours was the last number in her phone.
I am... so, so sorry, Ed.
Did she suffer?
No.
Anything you need, Ed,
anything at all,
I am here for you.
Breakfast!
Still collecting strays?
Lady,
you got two seconds to get out of here
before I gut you like a fish.
You really don't recognize me?
Selina, it's me.
Ivy? Hey, you got anything
to eat around here?
I'm starving.
Yeah.
Jim, I'm outside the
scene. Forensics found tons
of prints inside the bathroom
where Symon was attacked.
Barnes?
That just means he was in there.
- It puts him at the scene.
- Listen,
I've been thinking. You got to
tell Barnes what Symon said.
Give him the right to defend himself.
I will.
When I'm ready.
Help you?
Captain.
I was, uh, looking for
the Paulie Pennies file.
Thinking the cases might be related.
Thanks.
Fill me in.
Nothing hard yet, but we'll get there.
Uh-huh.
I was reading through some
of the witness statements.
The couple from the alley...
They say when they found
Symon, he was still alive.
You were first on the scene.
- Did he say anything to you?
- No.
He didn't ID the killer?
No.
Ah. 'Cause one of the
witnesses seems to think
that you were talking to him.
He tried, sure.
But he couldn't speak. He died
almost right away.
Uh-huh.
Well, for what it's worth, I called
an old C.I. of mine with
deep ties to the mob.
He says that
once I collared Symon,
the higher-ups got jumpy.
You're saying the mob had him killed?
He was giving these guys new faces.
He's probably the only
one who can ID them.
That's a lot to protect. Makes sense.
My C.I. also had a name.
Mid-level enforcer,
goes by "Sugar," works
out of the East End.
- Says he actually did the killing.
- I'll have a team pick him up.
I'd rather you kept this
between us. Mob still has
their fingers in most
of these guys' pockets.
You never know who you can trust. So,
you ready to ride with the old man?
Sure. Just let me run
it by my, uh, partner.
Why bother him?
We'll be there and back
before you know it.
So where are we headed?
Sugar works out of an old
foundry at 133rd and 6th.
Oh, that reminds me.
It's Harvey. Leave a message.
I'm with Barnes, heading
to 133rd and 6th.
Get there.
You never know what's gonna go down.
I have to say, Jim,
I'm disappointed with you.
Oh, yeah? How's that?
Lead detective for a
high-profile murder,
and you don't collect statements
from everyone present?
Me.
Well, let's do it now.
And for the record, I
waive my right to counsel.
- Captain...
- Ask your questions, Gordon.
Did you see Symon at the party?
Yes.
- Did you talk to him?
- No, I did not.
Did you see him go into the
bathroom before he was attacked?
Unfortunately, no.
Were you ever in it?
Yes.
Before it was a crime scene, obviously.
So, Detective, am I in the clear?
For now.
This city's a cesspool.
Don't you ever want to
do something about it?
I thought I was.
What, as a cop?
I would think that you, of all people,
would find that limiting.
Not anymore.
Came back to the GCPD
to do things right.
Like you.
- Like me?
- Last year,
at Galavan's, when we were attacked,
you told me the law shows
you where the line is.
That stuck with me.
Some would say that our
job, first and foremost,
is to protect the citizens of this city,
even if it means bending the laws.
No. We break the law, we're
no better than the criminals.
Is that what you were thinking
the night that Galavan was killed?
The first time.
This city's at a crossroads, Gordon.
Question is... Will
good men fight for it?
Will they do what's necessary?
The decision is yours to make.
You passed our stop. 133rd and 6th?
Did I say that?
136th and 3rd.
It's an honest mistake.
- Mmm.
- I don't believe it.
- Well, I should have known.
I saw what that freak Marv could do.
How he could age people, and when
he told me that the girl wearing
her sweater was older, I...
I should have realized.
That's really Ivy.
Trust me.
She came, and literally ate all my food.
Immediately ate all my food.
It's her.
So why is she back here?
Good question.
Ow! What was that for?
For being alive and not telling me!
I'm sorry.
I was just having fun.
Why did you come back?
I don't have to answer your questions.
Why'd you call him anyway?
'Cause you freaked me out!
Where have you been, and
why are you dressed like that?
Oh, it's so crazy, Selina.
When you look like this,
guys just come up to
you and give you stuff.
Half the time, you don't
even have to steal it.
Hmm. And what do you give them?
Hmm. I have ways of getting what I want.
- I'll bet.
- You do look nice.
So why did you come back?
And don't say it's 'cause you missed me.
It's true.
You may be ten feet tall, but
you're still a crappy liar, Ivy.
What's... going... on?
Well, I might be in trouble.
- I knew it.
- There was this guy...
- What was his name?
- Like I learn their names.
So I was at his place last night.
Total creep. Anyway, I stole a necklace.
I was surprised he noticed
'cause he had so much crap.
But he caught me, and
he totally freaked out.
If only Marv's power
had made you smart, too.
- You steal all the time.
- Yeah, well,
- I don't get caught.
- Shh.
Rude.
No. Be-be quiet.
I hear something.
We have to go.
Someone's here.
Ivy, in.
Bruce! Seriously?
So who is this guy again?
Just follow my lead.
GCPD!
- Don't move!
- Hey. Whoa. Whoa.
- Hiya, Sugar.
- What the hell is this?
We're here about the gas bill.
You're delinquent.
- Huh?
- Where were you
last night, say about 10:00 p.m.?
At your mama's, like always.
Answer the question.
I was at the fights.
A dozen people saw me.
A dozen of your lying,
bottom-feeding friends?
The name Symon mean anything to you?
- No.
- No?
Plastic surgeon? Face
man for your mob buddies?
Wait... No.
Like I said, so whatever the
hell you think I did, I didn't.
I was at the fights!
People saw me!
- I'm innocent, man!
- You know what?
I think he's telling the truth.
He didn't kill anyone.
But you're not innocent.
I think we lost them.
Is that who you stole the necklace from?
Uh, no. I-I don't think so.
Then who were they?
I don't know. Maybe they work for him.
Oh, great, Ivy! Now my squat is burned,
and masked weirdoes
are trying to kill us.
So glad you came back.
You have to return it.
What? No way.
Ivy, he's right.
That dumb necklace almost got us killed.
It's mine. I worked for it.
And it's super valuable.
- How much?
- Wait. Bruce, don't.
If I buy it, you get paid,
but we can still return it,
and those men will have
no reason to harm us.
How much?
- One thousand dollars.
- Fine.
Idiot.
- Two thousand.
- Fine.
Five... No. Ten!
Well, how much should I ask for?
I'll get you
$5,000 in cash today.
Or you can try to avoid
those men on your own.
That's my offer.
Now, where does this man live?
Now, just raise your chin a mite higher.
Would you excuse me for a moment?
Ed.
Yes.
The music!
It's too loud. I'm sorry!
Isabella always loved Vivaldi.
So you are just going to sit here.
- Yes.
- All by yourself.
Correct.
Okay then.
Apologies.
Ed, I, as much as anyone,
know how hard it is to lose someone.
Even if
you've only known them
for, like... a week.
But this is not healthy behavior.
It is depressing
and, if I'm being honest,
a bit scary.
Less scary.
Check.
No, you're not...
Ed, you need to heal.
And healing is about moving on.
No doubt you're right.
Of course I'm right.
I'll go to where she was taken from me
and say good-bye.
Isabelle would want you to be happy.
Isabella.
Of course.
That's good.
That's far enough.
I know what you're thinking, Jim.
You're thinking,
"Why would Captain Nathaniel Barnes,
"Mr. By-the-book, blow a hole
"in this unarmed scumbag?
Could it be that he
actually killed Symon, too?"
You see, I know that you've
been investigating me, Jim.
- Did you kill Symon?
- Is that
what he told you? I know he said
something to you before he died.
Yes, he did.
Probably the truest words
that bastard ever uttered.
And Paulie Pennies?
He chopped up bodies for murderers.
You gonna tell me he didn't deserve it?
That's for the law to decide.
Open your eyes, Jim.
I am the law.
What happened to you?
How did you become this?
This...
is who I've always been.
I just needed something to unlock it.
What are you talking about?
You're just gonna say that I'm sick.
Well, I'm not.
I have never been so clear,
so strong in my life.
Alice Tetch's virus.
The files on your desk. You're infected.
Oh, you are a detective after all.
Don't you see?
This means you're innocent. We c...
we-we can get you help.
Can we just skip the part
where you try to get
me to give myself up?
This isn't you. This is the virus.
No! I'm not insane.
And you are not seeing the big picture.
You're gonna frame me
for Sugar's murder.
That's up to you.
I deal in absolutes.
Black and white.
Innocence
and guilt.
Gotham, the people of this
city, need men like me,
men who can see what needs to be done
and have the courage to do it.
You have it within you
to be one of those men.
You want me to join you?
- Be a part of this?
- Oh, don't be so high and mighty.
You shot Galavan in cold blood.
And every day I wish I hadn't!
Thought I didn't have
a choice, but I did.
I lost my freedom.
I lost Lee.
I'd give anything to take it all back.
I didn't say it was easy,
Jim.
I said it was right.
Day after day, criminals
thumbing their nose at the law.
Well, today, I draw a line in the sand.
Only question is...
where do you stand?
Against you.
Well, I'm disappointed.
Good-bye, Jim.
Hey, Sugar! I got a... Whoa!
♪♪
And now I'm awake.
I wish I'd gone on sleeping.
I will never forget you, my love.
Good-bye, Isabella.
We are four blocks from her apartment.
Spare some change, sir?
I'm sorry,
you weren't, perchance, in this
area at 11:00 p.m. last night?
Uh-huh.
So d... You saw the accident?
Haven't seen nothin' for 20 years.
But I heard it.
Girl screaming, "Help! Help!"
- Then bang!
- I'm sorry,
she was screaming before the crash?
Well, she were dead after.
But you d... you
definitely heard screaming?
Yep. Blood-curdling.
How... odd.
I'll give him the necklace
and explain there's no
need for further violence.
Maybe I shouldn't be here.
I kind of hit him over
the head with a vase.
'Course you did.
Door's open.
I did not do that.
We really got to go.
- Bruce.
- It was the men that came after us.
He was killed by the same weapon.
- I thought they worked for him.
- Oh, looks like
you were wrong again, Ivy.
Can we leave now?
Why is this necklace so important?
What'd make someone kill for it?
Who cares?!
Are you crazy? That's worth $5,000.
Whoa.
What is it?
A key.
We should really go, Bruce.
Oh, my God.
You two are a couple now?
- No.
- Yes.
We're not?
I'm not talking about this right now.
We need to go somewhere right now.
And my place is toast,
thanks to this dimwit.
We'll go to my house.
You just had to come back.
Alvarez, hey,
- what is all this?
- Barnes called in.
Gordon went loco. Shot
an unarmed suspect,
then tried taking out Barnes, too.
No, no, no, no. This is not right.
Harvey, if I was you,
I'd find your partner,
have him come in quiet.
Otherwise, he's going down.
Jim? Hey.
Where the hell are you? Half
the precinct's looking for you.
Barnes killed Symon and Paulie Pennies.
And he just murdered someone
right in front of me!
What? I was
gone for, like, an hour.
He's infected with Alice Tetch's blood.
He's lost his mind.
He's trying to kill me.
- Oh, sweet gentle virgin...
- I need your help, Harvey.
- Okay, where are you?
- The old foundry.
Jim? Jim?
J...
Harvey, what's going on?
- They said Jim killed someone?
- It's a lie. It's Barnes.
It's Barnes. He's infected
with the Alice Tetch virus.
Oh, my God.
He was there when she died.
Yeah, and I figure we
got, like, ten minutes
before those trigger-happy
kill-bots find Jim
and take him out.
Harvey, you have to tell them.
Come on, they're not gonna believe me.
But they will believe
the medical examiner.
- What are you asking me to do?
- I need you to trust Jim.
Because right now,
you and I are all he has.
Stop!
Sorry, Jim.
End of the line.
Just as I suspected.
The brake lines are cut!
How is it...
that not one single
ignoramus from the GCPD
noticed that the brake lines were cut?
I don't know.
Someone paid 'em off.
The question is, who?
Who has that kind of
money and influence?
You don't know.
But I do.
End of the line.
No more running.
Just in time. In a few moments,
your brothers in arms are
gonna come up those stairs
and find your dead body,
and they'll believe me
when I tell them that
Jim Gordon is a killer.
It's a shame, really.
Could've made a great team.
Doesn't have to be this way.
You need help.
Are those really gonna
be your last words?
Nothing to say to Lee?
Go to hell.
Captain Barnes!
This is Detective Bullock.
You're under arrest.
Throw down your weapons
and come out with your hands up.
We know you killed Symon.
We know you killed Paulie Pennies.
We know you killed the
suspects in the East End.
You're infected with the Tetch virus.
The M.E. has proof.
Now, we don't want any bloodshed, Cap.
It's up to you.
No.
Thompkins and Bullock.
They lied for you.
They turned the whole
damn GCPD against me!
We're going in. Come on!
Don't.
You're under arrest.
Drop it.
No.
Don't make me do this.
I'm not making you do anything.
Stand down, Jim. Let me go.
If the cops want to hunt me, fine.
But you...
let me go.
I won't do that.
You would condemn this city
when I would save it.
You've got it all wrong.
You're just the same as I am.
I just have the guts to admit it.
No.
And I'll decide who I am.
Stand down.
No.
Then it is you that is guilty.
Jim, you okay?
Yeah.
I'm okay.
Holy cow. Don't get any ideas.
Okay, Mom.
Tomorrow we'll look into
what this all means.
Who those men in masks were.
For now, I'll have Alfred
make up beds for you both.
There's food in the
kitchen if you're hungry.
I could eat.
Surprise.
I hope I didn't mess things
up with your boyfriend.
I told you, he's not my boyfriend.
What happened?
Are you okay?
Yeah.
I'm fine.
And Barnes?
He's alive.
Bullock told me what you did.
- It was nothing.
- No.
You could've done nothing.
You didn't. I suppose I did
fabricate a blood test
stating that my superior
had a psychosis-inducing virus.
And I'm glad I did.
Me, too.
I suppose I better get going.
Lee?
Thank you.
Oswald!
Oswald. I need to speak with you.
Yes, but I have to show
you something first.
- This is important.
- So is this.
I was not compassionate this morning,
and I regret that.
What you are going through is terrible.
So...
You put me in your painting.
The artist went off a photograph,
but I think it's an excellent likeness.
Isabella was murdered.
What?
I went to the intersection
where she died.
It is four blocks from her apartment.
Who falls asleep four blocks
from their home? No one.
Also, a very fragrant homeless man
said that he heard her
scream before the crash,
so definitely not asleep. Now,
if she were awake, why didn't she brake?
- Why are there no skid marks?
- E-Ed, you are exhausted,
you are, you are emotional...
Her brake lines were cut!
Which leaves one conclusion.
Murder.
- No.
- Yes.
And I know who did it.
Who?
Butch.
- Butch?
- In retaliation.
For exposing him as the
leader of the Red Hood gang.
That makes perfect sense.
I swear to you, Ed, we will
find him and make him
pay for what he has done.
Thank you.
I knew I could count on you.
I feel like this office is cursed.
You think Barnes'll be all right?
I don't know.
I'm sorry I doubted you.
You didn't.
Not when it mattered.
This never happens.
Oleg!
www.tvsubtitles.net